# Joël De Leon Mayeu

joel-emmanuel@hotmail.com | 450-540-5777

# ABOUT ME

I am a passionnate, hard-working and very involved physics student. I'm currently in the 1st year of my MSc degree under the supervision of Pr. Tami-Pereg Barnea at McGill university. My research thesis will be on the subject of fermi arcs and effective surface models in Weyl semi-metals.

### HONORS & AWARDS

Physics Department Engagement Scholarship - University of Montreal 2023

Laurier de Bronze - Collège de l'Assomption 2020

#### **HOBBIES & INTERESTS**

- -Improvisation
- -Cooking
- -Cycling
- -Magic the Gathering and other board games

# **EDUCATION**

Cégep Marie-Victorin - DEC in natural sciences

2022-2023

University of Montreal - B.Sc. in physics

2020-December 2023

GPA: 4.195 out of 4.3

# RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

#### Laboratory of Pr. Philippe St-Jean - Research Intern

Summer 2022

- Simulation of topological materials using optical fiber loops
  - Study of the SSH model
  - Handling of tools such as oscilloscopes, waveform generators and high-precision lasers

#### Research team of Pr. Richard MacKenzie - Research Intern

2023

- · Qubit probe for edge states in an SSH chain
- · Effects of soliton inclusion on transmission
  - Study of the SSH model
  - Usage of numerical methods to find solutions
  - Usage of Green's functions to find analytical solutions
  - Study of transmission in an SSH chain with a soliton

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### University of Montreal - Teaching assistant

2022-2023

- Relativity 1 (Autumne 2022 and 2023)
- Classical mechanics 1 (Winter 2023)

# **FAECUM (Fédération des Associtations Étudiantes du Campus de l'Université de Montréal)** - Member of the PHARE (Programme contre le Harcèlement et pour des Actions Responsables et Éclairées) 2022-2023

· Prevention of sexual harassment in a student environment

• Security assistance in the context of festive events

#### Commission scolaire de Montréal - High school teacher

2024

- · Math teacher for two "Classes d'acceuil"
- · Science teacher for a sec. 4 class

McGill University - Teaching assistant 2024

· Teaching assisant for PHYS 131 in fall 2024

#### VOLUNTEERING

# **Physum** - Student Life Coordinator

2021-2022

- · Weekly organization of activities
- · Budget and inventory management
- · Communication with members

#### Café La Planck - Coordinator of volunteers

2022-2023

- · Communication with volunteers
- · Schedule creation
- · Budget management, money entry

#### Café La Planck - Treasurer

2023-2024

- · Budget management, money entry
- Payment of bills
- Communication with suppliers

#### CCUWiP 2024 - Webmaster

2023-2024

- Fundraising for CCUWiP
- · Maintenance of the conference's website